<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Geometric Properties on MPM2DP-0A Summative</title>
    <link>https://nyiyui.ca/mpm2dp-0a/p1/u2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Geometric Properties on MPM2DP-0A Summative</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 12:29:47 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nyiyui.ca/mpm2dp-0a/p1/u2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Properties of Circles</title>
      <link>https://nyiyui.ca/mpm2dp-0a/p1/u2/c/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 02:25:19 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nyiyui.ca/mpm2dp-0a/p1/u2/c/</guid>
      <description>Diameters of circles intersect at the centre of the circle.
Chords are line segments that join 2 points on curves (e.g. circles).
Right bisectors of chords pass through the centre of circles.
There is only one circle that passes through three non-colinear points.
A circumference of a triangle is a circle that passes through all three vertices of a triangle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Verify Properties of Triangles</title>
      <link>https://nyiyui.ca/mpm2dp-0a/p1/u2/vt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Dec 2021 23:40:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nyiyui.ca/mpm2dp-0a/p1/u2/vt/</guid>
      <description>The midpoint, length of line segment, and slope formulas can be used to verify properties of triangles (and sometimes in many ways!).
There are some shortcuts for some calculations involving horizontal and vertical lines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Properties of Quadrilaterals</title>
      <link>https://nyiyui.ca/mpm2dp-0a/p1/u2/q/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2021 17:30:22 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nyiyui.ca/mpm2dp-0a/p1/u2/q/</guid>
      <description>The diagnoals of a parallelogram bisects each other.
Joining the midpoint of adjacent sides of any quadrilateral forms a parallelogram.
You can use the formulas for lengths, midpoints and slopes to verify properties of quadrilaterals, just like triangles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Properties of Triangles</title>
      <link>https://nyiyui.ca/mpm2dp-0a/p1/u2/t/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2021 23:54:10 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nyiyui.ca/mpm2dp-0a/p1/u2/t/</guid>
      <description>Circumcentre The circumcentre is the intersection of all of the perpendicular bisectors of the sides of a triangle.
 It is equidistant from the vertices inside in acute triangles outside in obtuse triangles on $M_c$ where $c$ is the hypotenuse in right triangles  Figure 
 Description  How to construct the circumcenter of a triangle. Also shows how to construct a circle through given three points. Made with &amp;lt;a href=&amp;#34;https://en.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
